Jeff Gers Colorado, U.S.A. ♦ Cell: 303-803-5466 ♦ Email: jeffgersfx@gmail.com

Vision: User experience-focused QA Engineer with a passion for exploratory Mobile/Web testing, and a recent background creating iOS and Web UI end-to-end automation scripts that facilitate efficiency and consistency with release validations.

Test Tools and Methodologies

XCode, Android Studio, Postman, Chrome Dev Tools, Charles Proxy, Cypress.io, GitHub, Agile, Scrum, Kanban

Recent Professional Experience

Weve (Current) | Software QA Engineer (contractor)

TrueCoach (2019) | Software QA Engineer (contractor)

- Built Release Validation Test Plans for iOS applications
- Spun up simple Cypress.io Web UI automation frameworks for release validations

DispatchHealth (2019) | Software QA Engineer

- Built and maintained simple XCUITest and Cypress.io UI automation scripts for native iOS and Web applications
- Utilize Chrome Dev Tools to troubleshoot network, web socket and UI bugs for internal Web products
- Product support responsibilities including daily triage, investigation and resolution communication
- New feature and release validation of Android, iOS and both internal and external Web applications

Blinker, Inc (2015 - 2019) | Software QA Engineer

- Built and maintained a lightweight, yet extensive, native XCUITest UI automation framework for iOS application
 - Ran and debugged test suites during Releases
 - Used the framework as a tool for quickly getting into particular application flows
- Contributed to a Cypress.io Web UI automation framework.
 - Some experience building cypress.io tests with reusable methods for exercising various web flows
- Validated API endpoints and mutations using Postman and Insomnia
- Test and troubleshoot iOS, Android, web and responsive web applications as well as internal tools
 - Used native development solutions for debugging and automating
 - Consistently discovered high volumes of bugs that were the most impactful to the user keen eye for UI
 - Helped define specs, user experience, acceptance criteria, and contributed to prototypes for new functionality
 - Vocal member during elaborations who forced teams to think critically about user experience
- Key contributor to weekly release management process of Mobile products
 - o Implemented the process of running iOS automation suite against releases
 - o Reduced RC test cycle time from 3-5 days of manual testing to 1 hour of automated testing
 - Assisted with build management re: HockeyApp and distribution of apps for internal testers
- Worked with Support and Tech Operations teams regularly
 - o Assisted with reproducing difficult customer issues and escalation for triage
 - o Collaborated with Ops/Support team members to build better internal tooling to make their lives easier

Past Professional Experience

- Black Pixel (2013-2015) | Mobile QA Engineer (for multiple clients)
- MOGL (2013) | Mobile QA Engineer
- Ubermind/Deloitte Digital (2011-2012) | Mobile QA Engineer (for multiple clients)
- GoDaddy, Inc (2010-2011) | QA Engineer
- Photobucket/Fox Interactive Media (2006-2010) | QA Engineer, Legal Compliance/Product Knowledge Manager

Education

- B.A. Visual FX-Motion Graphics, 2005: Art Institute of Colorado, Denver, CO (Graduated with honors)
- Photography-Electronic Media, 2000-2002: University of Colorado, Boulder, CO

Mobile App Testing Contributions

Eaton PowerEdge, Every Body Walk!, MOGL, Starbucks, New York Times Now, New York Times Opinion, Storybird, Inspirato, Blinker, DispatchHealth, TrueCoach, Weve